
class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}


List<QuestionModel> questions = [
  QuestionModel(question: "1. In which type of circuit does the current flow continuously in one direction?",
      options: [
"a) AC circuits",
"b) DC circuits",
"c) Both AC and DC circuits",
"d) Neither AC nor DC circuits",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'n a DC circuit, the current flows continuously in one direction.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "2. What is the frequency of standard household AC power in the United States?",
      options: [
"a) 50 Hz",
"b) 60 Hz",
"c) 120 Hz",
"d) 240 Hz",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Standard household AC power in the United States has a frequency of 60 Hz.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "3. Which of the following components is used to convert AC to DC in electronic devices?",
      options: [
"a) Transformer",
"b) Capacitor",
"c) Diode",
"d) Inductor",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Diodes are used to rectify AC to DC in electronic devices.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. What is the peak voltage of a sinusoidal AC waveform with a root mean square (RMS) voltage of 120 V?",
      options: [
"a) 120 V",
"b) 169.7 V",
"c) 240 V",
"d) 340.5 V",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The peak voltage of a sinusoidal AC waveform is √2 times the RMS voltage, so it's approximately 120 V * √2 ≈ 169.7 V."
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "5. In an AC circuit with a purely resistive load, what is the phase relationship between current and voltage?",
      options: [
"a) In-phase (0° phase difference)",
"b) 90 degrees out of phase",
"c) 180 degrees out of phase",
"d) 270 degrees out of phase",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: ' In a purely resistive AC circuit, the current and voltage are in-phase, meaning they have a 0° phase difference.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "6. Which type of circuit element stores energy in a magnetic field and resists changes in current?",
      options: [
"a) Resistor",
"b) Capacitor",
"c) Diode",
"d) Inductor",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'An inductor stores energy in a magnetic field and resists changes in current.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the electrical symbol for a diode in a circuit diagram?",
      options: [
"a) R",
"b) C",
"c) D",
"d) L",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: ' The electrical symbol for a diode in a circuit diagram is represented by the letter "D."'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "8. In a DC circuit, a 10-ohm resistor has a current of 5 amperes passing through it. What is the power dissipated in the resistor?",
      options: [
"a) 25 W",
"b) 50 W",
"c) 100 W",
"d) 250 W",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'The power dissipated in a resistor can be calculated using the formula P = I²R.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "9. In an AC circuit, a capacitor has a capacitance of 0.02 F. If the frequency is 50 Hz, what is the capacitive reactance?",
      options: [
"a) 15 ohms",
"b) 20 ohms",
"c) 25 ohms",
"d) 30 ohms",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Capacitive reactance (Xc) is calculated using the formula Xc = 1 / (2πfC).'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "10. In a DC circuit, three resistors with values of 10 ohms, 20 ohms, and 30 ohms are connected in series. If a current of 2 amperes flows through the circuit, what is the total voltage drop across the resistors?",
      options: [
"a) 20 V",
"b) 40 V",
"c) 60 V",
"d) 120 V",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'In a series circuit, the total voltage drop is the sum of the voltage drops across each resistor.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "11. In an AC circuit, the real power is 400 W, and the apparent power is 500 VA. Calculate the power factor of the circuit.",
      options: [
"a) 0.4",
"b) 0.5",
"c) 0.6",
"d) 0.8",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Power factor (PF) is calculated as the ratio of real power (P) to apparent power (S), i.e., PF = P / S.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. In a DC circuit, two resistors with values of 40 ohms and 60 ohms are connected in parallel. What is the total resistance of the parallel combination?",
      options: [
"a) 24 ohms",
"b) 40 ohms",
"c) 60 ohms",
"d) 100 ohms",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: ' In a parallel circuit, the total resistance (Rp) is calculated as 1 / Rp = 1 / R1 + 1 / R2.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "13. In an AC circuit, a coil with an inductance of 0.1 H has a frequency of 60 Hz. What is the inductive reactance?",
      options: [
"a) 3.77 ohms",
"b) 7.54 ohms",
"c) 15.08 ohms",
"d) 30.16 ohms",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Inductive reactance (Xl) is calculated using the formula Xl = 2πfL.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "14. In a DC circuit with two resistors in series (R1 = 20 ohms and R2 = 30 ohms), if the total voltage is 60 V, what is the voltage drop across R2?",
      options: [
"a) 10 V",
"b) 20 V",
"c) 30 V",
"d) 40 V",

      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'In a series circuit, the voltage across each resistor depends on the ratio of its resistance to the total resistance.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "15. Which of the following statements is true about AC voltage and DC voltage?",
      options: [
"a) AC voltage has a constant magnitude.",
"b) DC voltage periodically changes direction.",
"c) AC voltage periodically changes magnitude and direction.",
"d) DC voltage is generated by a dynamo.",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'AC voltage periodically changes both magnitude and direction, while DC voltage remains constant.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "16. What is the power factor of a purely resistive AC circuit?",
      options: [
"a) 0",
"b) 1",
"c) 0.5",
"d) 0.707",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A purely resistive AC circuit has a power factor of 1, indicating that the current and voltage are in-phase.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "17. In an ideal diode, what is the voltage drop across it when it is conducting?",
      options: [
"a) 0 V",
"b) 1 V",
"c) 5 V",
"d) 10 V",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: ' In an ideal diode, when it is conducting (forward-biased), it has a voltage drop of 0 V.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "18. Which of the following components is used to smooth out voltage fluctuations in a DC power supply?",
      options: [
"a) Resistor",
"b) Capacitor",
"c) Diode",
"d) Inductor",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Capacitors are used to smooth out voltage fluctuations in a DC power supply.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "19. What type of circuit is commonly used in homes to control the intensity of light from lamps?",
      options: [
"a) AC circuit",
"b) DC circuit",
"c) Series circuit",
"d) Parallel circuit",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'AC circuits are commonly used in homes for controlling the intensity of light from lamps.'
  ),
  QuestionModel(question: "20. In an AC circuit with a purely capacitive load, what is the phase relationship between current and voltage?",
      options: [
"a) In-phase (0° phase difference)"
"b) 90 degrees out of phase"
"c) 180 degrees out of phase"
"d) 270 degrees out of phase"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: ' In a purely capacitive AC circuit, the current and voltage are 180 degrees out of phase.'
  ),
];